Seattle, WA 360.224.4251 alina.to@gmail.com helloalinato.com

ALINA TO

Software Developer

Full-stack software developer with experience building and launching mobile and web applications from proof-of-concept to store with tight deadlines. Focused on high quality client delivery, cross-browser test coverage, attention to detail, and efficiently refactored code.

TECHNOLOGY

JavaScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, AngularJS, ¡Query Objective-C, Java, C# HTML5/CSS3

Git, Test & Behavioral Driven Development MongoDB, SQL Google Cloud Services, Docker, Kubernetes Mocha/Chai/Enzyme, Selenium

TOOLS

Visual Studio, Sublime Text Android Studio, Xcode VirtualBox, Chrome Developer Tools Jira, Confluence, Trello Jenkins, TeamCity VMWare Postman

SKILLS

Agile, Kanban
Project estimation and story writing
Quick to learn new stacks and technologies
Testing/QA/Support
Collaboration and analysis with clients

EDUCATION

University of Washington – Seattle, WA

MA Teaching English 2008

BA Linguistics 2005

Code Fellows – Seattle, WA Certificate in Front-End Development 2015 Advanced Full-Stack JavaScript Development 2015

MongoDB University – Online Certificate of Completion in MongoDB for NodeJS 2015

CAREER HISTORY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / ACCESSIBILITY CONSULTANT

Foundry Interactive / Mar 2016 - May 2018

Seattle-based technology agency crafting client-based accessible mobile and web solutions. Clients include: Providence Health & Services, Change Healthcare, McKesson, Relay Health

Project: Web applications for healthcare online payment and internal tools

- Developed responsive frontend ReactJS web applications
- Built UI components from designs and acceptance criteria
- Developed Mocha and Enzyme ReactJS unit tests and performed cross-browser testing
- Developed C# page objects and web UI tests (Selenium)

Project: iOS and Android applications for pregnancy and parenting

- Developed native iOS / Android mobile applications with NodeJS backend and custom Diango CMS
- Performed full accessibility audit for iOS and Android mobile apps to meet WCAG compliance levels at A, AA, and AAA
- Developed mobile app features from designs and acceptance criteria
- Deployed app using Docker, Kubernetes, and Google Cloud Services
- Worked closely with QA team to analyze usability and catch bugs early
- Collaborated with other developers in code reviews and pair programming using Github
- Worked in Agile development process with daily scrum meetings and groomings
- Consulted with client on feature development advocating best practices and scalability

INDEPENDENT WEB CONSULTANT

Self-Employed / Dec 2014 - Present

Design and develop responsive mobile-first websites for small and midsized organizations. Develop completely from wireframes to prototypes to deployable product with appropriate styles

PROFESSIONAL VIOLINIST

Self-Employed / Apr 2008 - Present

Clients include: Macklemore, Fleet Foxes, Game of Thrones, Symphony Tacoma, Trans Siberian Orchestra, Al Gore

Perform violin in live performances and studio recordings. Collaborate and negotiate with fellow musicians and directors.